快跑 你能做到! 快! 快跑!
Run,you can make it! Run! Come on!
下一個
Next.
Darrin Call
Uh,darrin call.
沒有你的藥 不 不 不 我還有一瓶藥的
Oh,i don't have anything. No,no,no. I've got a refill left.
我叫Call 你能再查看一下嗎?
Could you justit's call. Can you just check that again?
我還有一瓶的
I have one refill.
沒有啊 不好意思
No,no,i'm sorry.
這可不大好 不大好...
It's notthat ain't good. That's not good.That's notit's just
你還好嗎?
are you ok?
快住手 住手
Make it stop!Justmake it
我得讓他停手 Call先生
i need to make it stop! Mr. Call
你不能幫幫我嗎? 給你藥 給 對不起
aren't you gonna help me? Hereyes,here. I'm sorry.
請住手
Just pleaseplease stop. Stop.
這不是我的! 不是我要的!
That's not it! That is not it!
我...
I justi just,uh
放鬆 沒事 沒事
relax. It's ok. it's ok.
還好嗎?
天啊! 哦 天啊!
God! Oh,my god!
哦 天啊 你還撐得住嗎?
Oh,my god, are you all right?
看看你都幹了些什麼!
Look what you've done!
快來人幫幫他
Please,somebody help him!
趕緊把刀放下
Put the knife down,now.
他還沒來
He's not in yet.
什麼?
What?
你在Hotch辦公室前晃了一小時了
You've been walking past hotch's office for an hour.
Emily去接他了
Emily's picking him up.
Hotch告我說他已經可以開車了
Hotch told me he was cleared to drive.
的確是這樣 但她想接他
He is. She wants to do it.
怎麼了?
What's going on?
Rossi 他剛休了一個月
He's only had a month off, rossi.
準確地講是34天
Technically,34 days.
你覺得足夠長嗎?
And you think that's long enough?
你覺得不夠? 那跟他說去
You don't? Tell him.
還是算了 我挺喜歡我工作的
No,thanks. I like my job.
你更喜歡他啊
You like him more.
他要是得了應激障礙綜合癥怎麼辦?
What if he's got ptsd?
他已經做過評估了
He was evaluated.
少來了 Rossi 那些題都是咱出的
Come on,rossi, we wrote those questions.
Hotch知道怎麼去答
Hotch knows exactly how to answer them.
那我們該怎麼辦? 對他做的一切都吹毛求疵?
So what are you gonna do, pick apart everything he does?
他應該離職多久? 一年? 兩年?
How long should he be gone? A year? 2?
只要Foyet逍遙法外一天 Hotch就算是輸了 你知道
Every day that foyet is out there,hotch loses, and you know that.
知道會讓Hotch怎樣嗎?
You know what that makes hotch?
注意力不集中
Distracted.
更有動力
Motivated.
Derek
Derek.
他回來是因為他必須這麼做
He's coming back because he has to.
他得知道我們是支持他的
He needs to know we've got his back.
他知道的
He knows that.
那就別讓他忘了
Then we don't let him forget it.
謝謝 痛嗎?
Thanks. Does it hurt?
只有想了才疼 可我老在想
It really only hurts when i think about it, which is pretty much all the time.
不 不 不 你別動
No,no,no.Get away,you. What?
這是給Hotch的
These are for hotch.
我的腿中槍了都不能吃曲奇哦
I get shot in the leg and i don't get any cookies.
你知道他不喜歡過度關心
You know he's gonna hate the attention.
這是曲奇 不是蛋糕
It's cookies,not cake.
反正估計他會裝作什麼都沒發生
He's probably gonna pretend like nothing happened,anyway.
但不意味著咱也得裝
Well,it doesn't mean we have to.
也許應該像平常一樣
I think maybe we should.
我不會這麼做的
I don't roll that way.
我一直在想
I've been thinking about it?
自從我認識Hotch以來 好像就沒見他眨過眼
The entire time i've known hotch, i don't think i've ever seen him blink.
是哦 很怪
I know. It's weird.
典型大男子主義者行為
Classic alpha male behavior.
你說他是不是把Foyet瞪怕了?
Do you think he stared down foyet?
也許吧 能救他的話
Maybe. If it would save his life.
你說他是不是一直盯著看 每一刀都盯著
Do you think he stared the whole time, like with each stab?
我不知道
I have no idea.
他還好嗎?
Is he ok?
換我肯定好不了 但...咱愛眨眼
I wouldn't be,but... I'm a blinker.
Spence 你在這啊 帶上你的包 發生什麼事了?
Spence,there you are. Grab your go bag. What's going on?
看看新聞
Turn on the news.
哪個台 隨便
Which one? It doesn't matter.
今晨8時剛過 一名叫Darrin Call的 40歲路易維爾當地居民
Just after 8:00 this morning, 40yearold darrin call, a lifelong resident of louisville,
襲擊了主道和特拉斯頓大道 拐角處藥房的顧客
assaulted customers at the pharmacy on the corner of main and truxton avenues.
目擊者稱襲擊後他朝大街東邊走去
Eyewitnesses saw him walking east on main street minutes after the attack.
自此再沒人見過他
He has not been seen since then.
我們要去路易維爾
We're going to louisville.
他身穿藍色襯衫 牛仔褲和淺灰外套
He was wearing a blue shirt,jeans, and a lightgray jacket.
政府當即召集各方追捕
Within the hour,the governor has called in all sources for a manhunt.
儘管全州追捕 嫌犯仍避開執法人員
Despite these statewide efforts, the suspect has eluded law enforcement.
傷亡人數正在上升
The body count is rising.
三人確認死亡 包括一名持槍 銀行保安 其槍支用於襲擊
3 are confirmed deadincluding an armed bank guard whose gun was used in the attack.
另外兩人仍傷勢危險
Another 2 remain in critical condition.
襲擊者尚未抓獲
The assailant is still out there.
我們將鏡頭交給Eric Jennings 他採訪了路易維爾居民...
We are going back to eric jennings who's been talking to residents of louisville
肯塔基州這案子瞭解多少了?
what do we know about this case in kentucky?
Call和受害人並無聯繫
Uh,there's no connection between call and his victims.
路易維爾警方搜查了該市 但他離開藥店後就沒有蹤跡了
Louisville p.D.'S covered the city, but there hasn't been any sign of him since he left the pharmacy.
查過他家了 家人?
You check his house,family?
當地警方在查
Locals are on it.
從最近經歷查起 找到刺激他的事
Start with his most recent history. Find the stressor.
別動
Uh,don't move.
準備好了? 你呢?
Ready? Are you?
我們在路易維爾的負責人 叫Kevin Mitchell
So our point person in louisville is lieutenant kevin mitchell.
早上好
Good morning.
高興見到你 一樣
Good to see you. You,too.
氣色不錯 謝謝
You look well,sir. Thank you.
要架多久?
How long do you have that?
不知道 歡迎回來 謝謝
I'm not really sure. Welcome back. Thank you.
有再次傷人嗎?
Any other attacks?
沒 還沒有 Call很難找
Um,no,not yet. Call's proven hard to track.
他沒有駕照 很可能還用走的
He's never had a driver's license, so he's most likely still on foot.
或公共交通工具
Or public transportation.
他不會坐公車的 到處都是他的照片
He's not gonna take the bus. His face is everywhere.
找到刺激他的事了嗎?
Has anyone found a stressor?
剛丟了工作 90年起就在一工廠幹活
He just lost his job. He's worked at a factory since 1990.
一直做器具 但從沒升過職
Made appliances since forever and not a single promotion.
現在才懷恨有點太久了
That's a long time to be bitter.
或者說他不在乎
Or he doesn't care.
要是有家人要養就不會
Not if he's got a family to feed.
實際上 他過隱居生活 據我所知 他沒有親人
Actually, he's of the hermit variety. As far as i can tell, he's got no one.
沒妻子 沒孩子 沒父母 生活沒什麼盼頭
No wife,no kids, no parents. Nothing to live for.
那他為什麼還沒自殺?
So why hasn't he killed himself yet?
這種太自由的人通常會自殺
Sprees usually end in suicide.
要是他活著沒盼頭 怎麼還不了結?
If he's got nothing to live for, why hasn't he ended it?
因為他還有沒做完的事 我們知道他表露出了憤怒
'Cause he isn't finished yet. We know he has displaced anger.
怒氣撒在第一個受害者身上
He took it out on the first victim.
理貨員代表著什麼人 我們得查清是誰
Well,the stock boy represents someone. We need to know who.
他參過軍嗎? 沒有
Is he military? Negative.
他發火捅人肯定有原因的
Well,he's lashing out for a reason.
這傢伙憤怒 有著無盡的目標 還拿著槍 他才剛剛開始呢
This guy's got anger, endless targets,and a gun, and he's just getting started.
犯罪心理 第五季 第2集 精神折磨
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode02 Haunted
艾米莉·狄金森寫到 "無需親臨幽室便能體味精神折磨
Emily dickinson wrote, "one need not be a chamber to be haunted.
無需親臨暗宅
"one need not be a house.
思想能帶你穿越置身其中"
The brain has corridors surpassing material place."
好了
all right.
64和65號州際公路的州界線以及
We've got checkpoints at the state line on both i64 and i65
市區20里半徑內都設了檢查站
and within a 20mile radius of downtown.
我們認為他仍在步行
We think he's still on foot.
不到三個小時 按照每小時2.5英里步速計算
It's been just under 3 hours with an average walking speed of 2.5 miles per hour,
差不多在半徑8英里的範圍內
which rounds up to an approximate 8mile radius.
目前我們集中檢查這
Now,we've concentrated here.
第一反應隊開始搜查 8英里內的商戶和住戶
First responders started a hardtarget search of businesses and residences within that 8 miles.
你們也要加入他們 你們知道他長什麼樣子
You're gonna join 'em. You know what he looks like.
去找到他
Go find him.
我們查了Darrin Call一切能查的
We dug up all we could on darrin call.
還去了他公寓 沒什麼發現
Even went to his apartment. Didn't find much.
我們的探員過去了
We've got agents over there now.
別擔心 會有所發現的 你們什麼策略?
Don't worry, we'll fill it in. What's your strategy?
我們要弄清楚他接下來去哪
We try to figure out where he's headed next.
你們有水晶球?
You got a crystal ball?
大多自由殺手表面都很挑釁
Most spree killers are outwardly aggressive.
我們研究了Call的行為 而他不好鬥
We've studied call's behavior, and he's defensive.
第一名受害者 理貨員
First victimstock boy.
好傢伙 這還不好鬥呢
Boy,there's nothing defensive about that.
事實上是的 他被人碰了之後 才做出反應的
Actually,there is. Call doesn't react until he's touched.
是這讓他突然爆發的?
And that's what set him off?
每次都這樣 接觸 捅人 接觸 捅人
Happens every time. Contact,then stab, contact,stab.
你是說他並非有意傷害這些人?
So you're saying he didn't mean to hurt these people.
他進去的時候沒帶武器
He didn't go in there with a weapon.
他現在有兩把了
Well,now he's got 2.
我在新聞堣膚G他照片了
I just put his face all over the news.
人們會阻止他的
People are gonna stop him themselves.
我們什麼時候能開發佈會?
How soon can we have a press conference?
攝影組都已經在外面了
The camera crews are out front.
太好了 我打電話給Hotch 他是誰?
Great. Let me call hotch. Who's that?
我們的主管 他已經到犯罪現場了
Our supervisor. He's at the crime scene already.
這個孩子怎麼了?
What is it about this kid?
這就是我們想知道的
That's what we need to figure out.
Call的公寓離藥店5分鐘的路
Call's apartment is 5 minutes from the pharmacy,
但沒有他回來清洗血跡的跡象
but there's no sign that he came here to wash off that blood.
那他還滿身是血的在街上?
How's he still on the street, looking like that?
也許沒有
Maybe he's not.
Garcia說他沒有親人 那他能去哪?
Garcia said he's got nobody. Where would he go?
Call起床 疊好被子
Call gets up,he makes his bed.
確定他沒當過兵嗎?
We're sure he wasn't military?
房子看來是很整潔 也許住院接受過治療 我問問Garcia
It looks like one neat aspect. Maybe he was hospitalized. I'll call garcia.
那他生活也許很有規律
Then he's probably got the same routine every day.
除了今天
Except today.
他吃完麥片 走到藥店殺了3個人
He finished his cereal, walked to the pharmacy, and killed 3 people.
為什麼?
Why?
Call先生一般很少說話
Mr. Call was always so quiet.
他來這買東西好幾年了
He's been coming here for years.
他和理貨員有過爭執嗎?
Had he ever had a runin with the stock boy?
John是新來的 我招手叫他過來
John was new here. I waved him over.
我不知道該怎麼做 沒別人幫我了
I didn't know what else to do. No one else was helping.
你給了他處方後他才發狂的?
He didn't turn violent until you gave him his prescription?
那不是他的處方
Well,it wasn't his.
你給了他一袋
You handed him a bag.
那是別人的 我只是希望他能冷靜下來
It was somebody else's. I just wanted him to calm down.
JJ說發佈會5分鐘後開始
Jj's press conference is in 5 minutes.
Hotch 可能會有新發現 你為什麼不把他自己的藥給他?
Hotch,we might have something else here. Why didn't you give him his own medication?
他的藥已經用完了
Well,he didn't have any refills left.
什麼藥? 阿普唑侖(抗焦慮藥)
For what? Uh,alprazolam.
但他以前是用安定藥的
But,uh,he used to be on thiothixene.
他在用抗精神病藥物?
He was on an antipsychotic?
所以我才想讓他冷靜下來
Well,that's why i wanted him to calm down.
你說以前 他多久沒吃過這些藥了?
You said he used to be. How long has he been off of them?
至少一個月
At least a month.
你準備什麼時候才告訴我們?
And when were you gonna tell us this?
他有武器 神志不清 他的醫生是誰?
He's armed, he's delusional. Who's his doctor?
不記得了 我的電腦 真夠好的
I don't remember. My computer. Great.
對不起 真是太好了
I'm sorry. Great.
對不起 Hotch
Excuse us. Hotch.
告訴JJ藥的事 這不是她的錯
Call jj and tell her about the meds. This is not her fault.
Morgan 他精神病犯了 這就完全不同了
Morgan,he's in a psychotic break. It changes everything.
我們談談好嗎? 不! 我想找到他
You want to talk about this? No! I want to find him.
Garcia 他一個月沒吃精神抑製藥了
Garcia, he's been off his antipsychotic for a month.
你還漏掉了什麼?
What else did you miss?
對不起 我還沒查到他的病史 所以... 那就去查 查出他所有的事
I'm sorry,sir. I didn't get his medical records yet,sowell,find them.Find everything.
知道了...
Yes... Sir.
對不起
Excuse me.
我給人看病!
I'm in a session!
我要藥 Darrin 怎麼了? 發生什麼事?
I need the pills. Darrin,what's wrong? What happened?
他有一把...一把刀 誰?
He had aa knife. Who?
和惡夢堛漱@樣
It's just like in the nightmares.
他 他又在那麼做了
Hehe's doing it again.
他傷不了你 我們談過這些了
He can't hurt you. We talked about this.
你想記起來 所以才停藥了
You want to remember. It's why you're off the pills.
你說我會好些的 你確實好些了
You said i would get better. You are.
我這樣像好些了嗎?
Does it look like i'm better?
Darrin Darrin
Darrin. Darrin.
我要...
I gotta...
阻止他
Make it stop.
停下! 停... Darrin...
Make it stop! Just make itmake it... Darrin...
冷靜 看這 停...停...
Calm down. That's it.Just look here. Make itmake it
深呼吸 深呼吸
just breathe. Take a breath.
他沒帶武器 本沒打算傷害任何人
He was unarmed. He didn't mean to hurt anyone.
他只是想要藥 但他沒拿到
All he wanted was his medication, but he didn't get it.
他需要幫助
He needs help.
Call的醫生是誰?
Who's call's doctor?
州派精神病醫師Charles Cipolla
State appointed psychiatrist charles cipolla.
Hotch和Morgan去找他了
Hotch and morgan are on their way.
他的辦公室在哪?
Where's his office?
康登和第三大道交口
Camden and third.
Cipolla沒接電話 定位系統顯示還有5分鐘路程
Cipolla's not picking up. Gps says were 5 minutes away.
Rossi 我們5分鐘後到 告訴Mitchell到那見
Ok,rossi,we're 5 out. Tell mitchell to meet us there.
Darrin? Darrin?
不! 不! 洗乾淨! 洗乾淨! Darrin
No! No! Get it out! Darrin.
不! 洗乾淨! 不!洗乾淨! Darrin!
No!Get it out!No,get it out! Darrin!
洗不 我洗不乾淨! 我要
Can't get iti can't get it out! I can'tgotta
Darrin 我要洗乾淨!
Darrini gotta get it out!
Darrin 這 這 Darrin 這 穿我的衣服 拿著
darrin,darrin,here. Here. Darrin! Darrin,here. Take my shirt. Just take it.
這樣就好了 很好
There you go, that's good.
不! 別碰他!
No! Don't touch him!
Darrin 不要!不! 天哪!不!天哪!
Darrin,no! No! Oh,my god! No! Oh,my god!
好了 都出去 搜查周圍 現在就去
All right,get out of here and check the perimeter. Do it now.
我們太晚了
We're too late.
Hotch!
他洗乾淨了 換了衣服 據我所知還有可能染了頭髮
He cleaned up, changed his clothes, could have dyed his hair for all i know.
Call精神病發
Call's suffering from a psychotic break.
他不是特意逃避我們
He's not dodging us on purpose.
不是吧 相信我
Oh,come on. Trust me.
他有精神病 醫生幹嘛還給他停藥?
If he was psychotic, why would his doctor take him off the drugs?
Call沒有暴力行為的歷史
Call has no history of violent behavior.
Cipolla也不知道會發生這些
Cipolla couldn't predict that would happen.
看看這個地方
Look at this place.
是啊 很亂
Yeah,it's a mess.
不 不光是亂
No,it's more than that.
Call在找什麼東西
Call was looking for something.
對 找藥
Yeah,the drugs.
醫生不把藥放在這
Doctor doesn't keep the drugs here.
處方本還在桌上
Scrip pad is still on his desk.
我猜他是來尋求幫助的
My guess is he came here for help.
他的檔案不見了
His file's missing.
寶貝 怎麼了
Yeah,baby girl, what's going on?
Hotch呢? 他沒接電話
Where's hotch? He's not answering.
在外面 他沒事
He's outside. He's all right.
你確定? 是 怎麼了?
Are you sure? Yeah. What's up?
神秘事件
A mystery.
Garcia 拜託 今天別開玩笑 我知道 是這樣的
Come on, not today,garcia. I know. Here's the deal.
我漏掉抗精神病藥後... 聽我說 這不是你的錯
When i missed the antipsychoticslisten to me.That was not your fault.
你總護著我 親愛的 但我覺得是
You are ever my champion,sugar, but i believe it was.
不管了 我漏掉了 於是又從頭查 但是根本沒有頭
Anyway,when i did that, i went back to the beginning for call,except there is no beginning.
等等 Rossi
Wait a minute. Rossi.
再說一次 你在說什麼?
Say that again. What are you talking about?
Darrin Call從1969年到1975年不存在
Darrin call didn't exist like from 1969 to 1975.
沒有出生證明 沒社保 沒身份 什麼都沒有 直到他6歲
There's no birth certificate, no social security, no identity,nothing, until he was 6 years old.
他被父母拋棄了?
Was he abandoned?
我最不喜歡的三個字不知道
My least 3 favorite words strung togetheri don't know.
我猜他自己也不知道
My guess is neither does he.
我該從錄像媯o現他眨眼的
I should have seen the blinking on the video.
可能只是緊張抽筋呢
Well,it could have been a nervous tic.
但不是 是長期服用抗精神病藥 的典型癥狀 而我忽略了
But it wasn't. It's a classic sign of longterm antipsychotic use, and i missed it.
我們都忽略了
We all did.
不管怎樣 他們死了
Well,regardless, those men died.
Garcia有發現
Garcia's got something.
1975年5月1日 6歲的Darrin Call 在偏僻的地方流浪 被人發現並帶走
May 1,1975, a 6yearold darrin call was found roaming in the middle of nowhere and was picked up
最開始幾個月在孤兒院
and was in state care for the first few months.
他告訴警察發生什麼事了嗎
Did he tell the cops what happened?
沒有 因為他一年多都沒說話
No. Because he didn't talk, not for over a year.
而當他開口說話時 就只知道Darrin Call這個身份了
And once he started talking, he only knew his life as darrin call.
太可憐了 接下來也是
That's awful. So is this.
小Darrin從沒被人認領
Little darrin was never claimed.
也許他不是那一帶的人
Maybe he wasn't from the area.
1975年還沒有完善的失蹤兒童系統
There wasn't a thriving missing children's network in 1975.
Call穿著Cipolla的衣服
Call is wearing cipolla's clothing.
你認為他頭腦清醒的?
You think he's lucid?
不 很可能他只是嚇壞了
No,mostly likely he's just freaked out.
不管怎樣 我們應該告知公眾最新消息
Either way,we should update the public.
你也應該去
You should be there,too.
這是什麼? Call的時間表
What is this? Call's timeline.
他離開路易斯維爾? 3次
He left louisville? 3 times.
總是回到那10個街區內? 為什麼?
Always came back to the same 10block radius. Why?
受害人總會被最初受傷的地方吸引
Victims are often drawn to the scene of their first trauma.
他既想逃離 又掙扎著想找到答案
Part of him wanted to escape, the other part probably struggled to find answers.
他住院治療過嗎?
Was he hospitalized?
1985年 治了2年
Uh,1985 for 2 years.
沒錯 然後95年也有幾個月 都在費耶特縣的公共醫院
Yeah. And again in '95 for a few months, both at the state facility in fayette county.
你們知道他不會開車
You know he doesn't drive.
難道他會自己走過去嗎?
You think he'd walk all the way out there?
他不顧一切 會找到方法的
He's desperate. He'll find a way.
那我告訴費耶特的警長
Well,then i'll tell the sheriff in fayette.
他什麼時候開始服藥的?
When did he start the prescriptions,garcia?
1977年 似乎什麼藥都吃過了 我找到一張清單
In 1977,and it looks like he tried them all. I've got a list.
按字母順序 阿普唑侖 氯硝西泮 安定...
Alphabetically,alprazolam, clonazepam,diazepam
發給我 是
just send it. Yes,sir.
醫生讓他停藥肯定有理由的
His doctor weaned him off the prescription for a reason.
風險很大 肯定是為了更有利的事
Now,that's a big risk, so the reward must have been greater.
他要知道真相
He needs the truth.
他拿走了他的檔案 找到了些答案
He took his file. He's got some answers.
讓他搶先一步
And a head start.
那我們就追上他
Well,we need to catch up.
傷疤/創傷
SCARS / TRAUMA
意識喪失
BLACKOUTS
遺棄/忽視
ABANDONMENT / NEGLECT
兒童服務機構記錄到 他受到嚴重的虐待
Records from child services has him extremely physically abused.
沒有性暴行的跡象
No signs of sexual assault.
這是個奇跡
That's a miracle.
不管怎樣 創傷使他身體虛弱
Either way,the trauma was debilitating.
他是為了逃離家庭虐待還是綁架?
Was he running from an abusive home or an abduction?
如果是誘拐會沒有記錄嗎?
Wouldn't there be a paper trail if it were a kidnapping?
Garcia 查一下1970年後 未偵破的兒童失蹤案
Garcia,look for unsolved missing children's cases from the 1970s.
谷溪鎮有個案子
Now,there was a case in hollow creek.
但被綁的孩子都死了 屍體不完整
Kids were dead,though. Found them in pieces.
什麼時候的事? 1975年
When was this? '75.
沒人說起這事 因為沒找到兇手
Nobody talks about it 'cause they never found the guy.
你覺得Call是這案子的生還者?
You think call walked away from that?
有可能 Garcia 資料發給我 好了
It's possible. Garcia,send me everything. Done.
你能找到案子資料嗎?
Can you find the case file?
我盡力
I'll do what i can.
You're it! Come on,wait up!
有嫌犯名單嗎?
Is there a suspect list?
就在這堶
It's in here somewhere.
他被稱為谷溪鎮殺手
He was known as the hollow creek killer.
發現3具屍體 有些未證明身份
3 bodies were found, some never identified.
天哪 他用石灰處理...
Oh,god,he used lime to dispose
有一個倖存者 Call?
there's a survivor. Call?
不 一個叫Tommy Phillips的12歲男孩
No,a 12yearold boy named tommy phillips.
父母說他失蹤了兩星期 回來後大不一樣了
Parents said he'd been missing for 2 weeks, came back a different kid.
那是肯定
Of course he did.
Tommy告訴警察屍體位置後 他們全家就離開了路易斯維爾
Let's see. The family left louisville after tommy told police where to find the bodies.
他還說嫌犯是30多歲的白人 開一輛紅色輕型卡車
He also said the suspect was a white man in his 30s and drove a red pickup truck.
我們得找到Tommy
We need to find tommy.
他現在46歲了
He'd be 46 now.
他父母可能給他改了名字 有多遠走多遠了
His parents probably changed his name and got as far away as possible.
Garcia能找到他
Garcia can find him.
別抱太大希望了
Don't get your hopes up.
Garcia 查Tommy Philips的所有資料
Garcia, everything you can find on a tommy phillips.
受害人身上有刀痕
The victims had cuts.
是藥店理貨員的小刀刺激了他
The stock boy's blade is what set him off in the pharmacy.
如果Call是在逃避這個 也難怪他會封閉這些記憶
If this is what call's been running from, it's no wonder he's blocked it out.
現在停藥了 他的記憶就甦醒了 他想討個答案
Since he's clean now, there's no medication to block his memories and he wants answers.
他會去哪呢?
Where would he go?
去他知道的地方
To what he knows.
他什麼都不知道 這才是問題
He doesn't know anything. That's the problem.
他正在慢慢恢復記憶
He's beginning to.
1975年 Sterner孤兒院
1975,sterner orphanage.
那是他成為Darrin Call的地方
It's where he became darrin call.
找誰?
Yes?
這兒有個好人 Cureton先生
There was a nice man here,mr. Cureton.
我要見他
I need to see him.
不好意思 他幾年前就退休了
I'm sorry, he retired years ago.
那他去了哪? 我也不知道 對不起
Well,where did he go? I don't know.I'm sorry
你一定知道! 他不會就這麼走掉的
you gotta know! Hehe didn't just leave.
對不起 先生 可我說了 他不在這
I'm sorry,sir, but i told you, he's not here.
過來 孩子們 做作業了! 過來 來
Come on,kids,homework! Come on. Come on.
請您離開好嗎? 孩子們要進屋了 走吧
Would you please leave? The children are coming in. Please.
來 來 去看書吧 馬上去
Come on. Come on. Straight to the books. Right to it.
去後屋坐下來
Straight to the back and we'll sit down.
他在這兒
He's here.
他在這兒 誰? 你說什麼呢?
He's here. Who? What are you talking about?
沒人在這 他在這 我剛...
Nobody's here. He's here.I just
哦 小心 Ryan
oh,careful,ryan.
過來啊 你行的! 來! 來 過來!
Come on,you can make it! Come on! Come on,come on!
Tommy Tommy 我們得離開這
Tommy,tommy, we gotta go.
不 等等 住手! 住手! 住手!
No,waitstop it!Stop it! Stop it!
我們走 Tommy
Come on,tommy.
救命啊! 來人啊! 我們必須得跑
Somebody help! Somebody!
謝謝你
Thank you.
他管那孩子叫Tommy
He called the boy tommy.
這是刺激他的誘因?
Is that what set him off?
她覺得是他倒影刺激的
She thought it was his reflection.
多年前傷害他的人 可能和他現在差不多大
Whoever hurt him years ago might have been the same age he is now.
他可能看到了相同點
He might have seen the similarity.
那孩子什麼狀況?
What about the boy?
真名叫Ryan 她說是個安靜順從的孩子
His real name is ryan. She said he's quiet and submissive.
Morgan有沒有從其他目擊者那 得到什麼信息?
Is morgan getting anything out of the other witness?
還沒
Not yet.
離這一個街區 有輛小貨車被偷了
A minivan was stolen one block from here.
Call從來沒開過車
Call's never driven in his life.
你還認為他不是躲避我們嗎?
You think he's still not running from us?
走的哪條路? 向東那條
Which way? Eastbound.
我在附近都布下了路障
I got roadblocks set up everywhere.
他跑不出這個縣
He's not getting out of this county.
你這是在浪費時間
You're wasting your time.
他們才兩個人
He's outnumbered.
你覺得他能就這麼憑空消失?
You think he's gonna just disappear?
我認為他帶走孩子是有原因的
I think he took the boy for a reason.
我才不管他為什麼帶走那孩子
I don't care why he took him.
你應該關心一下 Call的記憶已經釋放了
You should. Call's memory is no longer suppressed.
他在重建過去 除非我們弄懂 否則他們倆我們誰也找不到
He's reinventing his past, and unless we understand how, we're not gonna find either of them.
我可不會就這麼乾坐著瞎猜
Well,i'm not gonna just sit around and speculate.
那就別
Then don't.
你也認為我們不該去追他們?
You don't think we should chase him either?
我們得趕在Call前面
We need to get ahead of call.
現在可失蹤了一個孩子
There's a kid missing.
他們不需要人手
They don't need the extra manpower.
怎麼會?
Since when?
要是研究過Foyet最初的罪行 就該知道沒道理留倖存者
If we'd studied foyet's initial crimes, we would have known that a survivor didn't make sense.
他跟這案子有什麼關係?
What does he have to do with this?
我們要做的不過是放慢腳步 審視Foyet的過去 卻沒做到
All we had to do was stop and look at foyet's history, and we didn't,
導致很多無辜的人喪生
and we lost two couples and a bus full of people.
我不會再犯錯誤了
And i'm not making that mistake again.
他們會找到我們的 在哪? 你看見他了? 哪呢?
They're gonna find us. Where? You saw 'em? Where?
誰? 你在哪看到他了?
Who? Where did you seem 'em?
誰? 你在哪看到他了? 在哪?
Who? Where did you see 'em? Where?
求求你 放了我吧
Please,just let me go.
對不起 Tommy
I'm sorry,tommy.
只要...我們只要...只要
Justwe just gottawe gottajustohhwe gotta
我們要快跑 因為他會抓住我們 我們要...要...
we gotta hurry,tommy, 'cause he's gonna get us and we justwe just gottauhh
都瞭解些什麼?
so what do we know?
谷溪鎮案只有四名嫌疑人 而且都死了
There were only 4 suspects in the hollow creek case and they're all dead.
孩子分別是73年 74年 75年被綁的
The kids were taken in 1973,'74,and '75.
都是在放學回家的路上
And all on the way home from school.
不一樣的校區
Different school districts.
他一直等著他們落單
He waited for them to be alone.
這需要耐心 他下午一定不上班
That takes patience. He must have had time off in the afternoons.
他住在學校附近或在附近工作
He lived or worked near the schools.
那可有的問了
That's a lot of doors to knock on.
你覺得Call會故地重遊嗎?
You think call's going back there?
可能性很大
I think there's a good chance.
我去通知Mitchell
I'll tell mitchell.
第二地點是哪?
Where's the secondary location?
他需要隱藏起來做他做的事
He needed seclusion to do what he did.
說吧 Garcia 我開免提了
Go ahead,garcia. You're on speaker.
我查到Tommy了 現在叫James Thomas Anderson
I found tommy. He goes by james thomas anderson now.
是本地人嗎?
Is he local?
是鄰鎮的 地址和資料正在發送
One county over. Address and bio are coming... Now.
謝謝 Garcia
Thanks,garcia.
Darrin Call和我有什麼關係?
What does darrin call have to do with me?
我們認為他是谷溪鎮謀殺案的倖存者
We think he survived the hollow creek murders.
沒人倖存下來
Nobody survived that.
你不就是
You did.
當時還有一個男孩 六歲
There was another boy. He was 6.
沒有
No,that's not true.
我們沒空跟你玩
We don't have time for this.
跟你說了 當時就我自己
I'm telling you, i was alone.
就像現在?
Just like now?
你什麼意思?
Excuse me?
你結過婚嗎?
Have you ever been married?
有女朋友嗎? 家人呢?
Any relationships? Any family?
這些又有什麼關係?
What does that have to do with anything?
還是你害怕也會拋棄他們?
Or are you afraid you'll abandon them,too?
還是因為你是個酒鬼?
Or was it because of your alcoholism?
我絕不想丟下孩子的
I would never leave a kid.
是他太愛哭了?
Did he cry too much?
還是他太慢了? 究竟為什麼? 你怎能丟下一個六歲的孩子?
Was he too slow? What was it? How could you leave a 6yearold all alone?
我那時才十二歲
I was only 12 years old.
他一直在服用藥物治療 那次抑制他記憶的創傷
He's been taking medications to deal with the trauma that suppressed his memories.
這種失憶是心理防禦在起作用
That kind of amnesia is a psychological defense.
他會希望自己永遠記不起的
He's gonna wish he never remembered.
我們知道你告訴了警察什麼
We know what you told the police.
我們想瞭解那個男孩
We need to know about the boy.
他從來不說話
He never talked.
嘿 小孩 嘿 小孩
Hey,kid. Hey,kid.
那老傢伙睡過去沒?
Is the old man passed out yet?
你夠得著那個嗎?
Can you reach those?
好 很好
Good. Good.
很好 好了 拿過來
Good. Ok. Please. Bring 'em here.
繼續 你能做到的
Go ahead,you can do it.
我們走 走!
Come on. Come on!
拿上鏟子
Grab the shovel.
給我過來! 不許掙扎!
Hey,come here! Quit struggling!
過來
Come here.
出來
Get out of there.
走 走啊!
Come on. Come on!
過來 你能做到的!
Come on,you can make it!
過來 你行的! 過來! 過來啊!
Come on,you can make it! Come on! Come on!
跑啊 Tommy! 跑啊! 跑 Tommy! 跑!
Go,tommy! Run! Go,tommy! Run!
跑啊 Tommy! 跑!
Go,tommy! Run!
在那之前 我從沒聽過他說話
I'd never heard his voice before.
他讓你跑
He told you to go.
他還是個孩子
He was a kid.
你也是
So were you.
Call沒有和你一起關在後面
Call wasn't in the back with you.
沒有 他待在小屋
No,he was in the cab.
他給你水喝 弄到鑰匙
He gave you water. Got the keys.
為什麼他沒被關起來?
Why wasn't he locked up?
也許Call不是受害者
Maybe call wasn't a victim.
Call的倒影
Call's reflection.
哦 天
Oh,god.
他的父親就是谷溪鎮殺手
His father was the hollow creek killer.
他自己的孩子? 怪不得沒人來領呢
His own kid? No wonder he was never claimed.
他要怎麼解釋孩子突然失蹤呢?
How did the father explain his son just disappeared?
可能說他跑了
Could have said he ran away.
那媽媽會上報失蹤的啊
The mother would have reported him missing.
或許他說孩子死了
Maybe he said the boy died.
那她得辦葬禮啊
She'd want a funeral.
要是沒媽媽呢?
What if there wasn't one?
Morgan 打給Garcia 讓她查69年75年的死亡記錄
Morgan,call garcia. Ask her to check death records from 1969 to 1975.
查誰? 查母親
For who? For the mother.
跑啊 Tommy! 快跑! Tommy 快跑!
Go,tommy! Run! Go,tommy,run!
你以為你就沒事了? 你這麼想的?
You think you can get away? Is that what you think?
你個傻雜種
You stupid little bastard.
縮小範圍了嗎?
Have you narrowed it down?
6年時間太長了 再給我點特徵描述
Oh,6 years is a long time. I need more parameters.
她住在8英里半徑範圍內 已婚
She lived within that 8mile radius. She was married.
當年很可能是20多歲
She was most likely in her twenties.
他也許是她唯一的孩子 丈夫開一輛紅色卡車
He was probably her only kid. The husband drove a red truck.
好的 查到一個
Ok. This could be one.
Doris Jarvis 難產而死
Here we go,doris jarvis. Died in childbirth.
我猜猜 她生下一個男孩 對
And let me guessshe had a boy. Yeah.
寶貝兒 我開揚聲器 夥計們
Baby girl,i'm gonna put you on speaker. Guys.
Doris Jarvis嫁給了Bill Jarvis
Ok,so doris jarvis was married to bill jarvis.
他在市區外有一家機修店
He owned a machine shop just outside the city.
可能是第二地點
That could be the secondary location.
1980關門 從此什麼都沒做過 我猜他是低調行事
It closed in 1980. He hasn't done anything since. I guess he laid low.
他有輛紅色輕卡 直到76年 他買了輛黑的
He had a red pickup until 1976 when he bought a black one.
我之所以知道 是因為 他因酒後駕車被捕時就開的這輛
I know that because that's what he was driving when he was arrested for duis.
77到80年坐牢 現在就發他照片過去
He was locked up from '77 to '80, and i'm sending his picture now.
這肯定就是Darrin Call的爸爸了
And that could certainly be darrin call's father.
Jarvis現在在哪?
Where's jarvis now?
老地方 希金斯大街1457號 走
In the same house. 1457 hitchens avenue. Let's go.
你回來晚了
you're late.
就知道你會回家
I knew you'd come home.
副隊長 孩子在堶 我們控制中
Lieutenant. The kid's in there. We've got this.
特警隊員在看守出口
Tactical teams are covering the exits.
要牽引Call的注意力
Call needs a distraction.
他注意力都在老爸身上 現在是
He's focused on the old man. For now.
但我們還是得找最安全的辦法 把孩子救出來
But we're gonna have to figure out the safest way to get that kid out.
後面有隊人馬 還有一隊在路上
I've got a team in the back and one on the way.
我們要悄悄潛入
We're going to infiltrate.
這麼做的話 會出人命的
You do that and someone else dies.
要麼是Call  要麼是兒童謀殺犯 選吧
Either call or a child murdererflip a coin.
不一定非得這樣
It doesn't have to end like that.
讓Jarvis認罪然後走人 Call也就有了自己的答案
We get a confession out of jarvis and he goes away, and call gets his answers.
不需要再死人了
No one else has to die.
Hotch Hotch
Hotch. Hotch.
Hotch! 他這是幹嘛呢?
Hotch! What the hell is he doing?
讓他去 Rossi 我可不能讓他一人進去
Let him go. Rossi,i'm not letting him go in there solo.
我們得信任他
We have to trust him.
我們可以一起來
We can do this together.
出去! 我叫Aaron
Get out! My name's aaron.
這是我倆跟他之間的事
This is between us and him.
我知道
I know.
那你就別多管閒事
Then you leave us alone.
我知道他對那些孩子做了什麼
I know what he did to those boys.
我知道谷溪鎮和籠子
I know about hollow creek and the cage.
還有Tommy
And tommy.
你知道Tommy?
You know about tommy?
快 你能行的 快點! 快!
Come on,you can make it! Come on! Come on!
我們要讓他償還他所做的一切 Tommy
We're gonna get him back for everything that he done,tommy.
每一件事
Every single thing.
放他走 無需讓Tommy看到這個
Let him go. Tommy doesn't need to see this.
他該去死
He should die.
是的 但殺掉他的話 你什麼都得不到
He should.But if you kill him, you have nothing,
我想你想要答案吧
and i thought you wanted some answers.
他在做什麼?
What's he doing?
拖延時間
Stalling.
他是放手一搏了
He's got nothing to lose.
來啊 Darrin 問他
Go ahead,darrin, ask him.
你為什麼那樣對孩子們?
Why did you do that to those kids?
什麼孩子? 別裝!
What kids? No!
我們埋掉那些 為什麼?
The ones that we buried. Why?
你腦袋糊塗了 沒有!
You're confused. No!
Jarvis 你幹嘛不搬走?
Jarvis,why didn't you move?
這是我家
This is my home.
真不是因為外面的景? Darrin 來
You sure it's not the view? Darrin,come here.
過來看看
Come take a look at this.
他每天坐在走廊上看孩子
He sits on the porch every day and watches those kids.
他控制不住自己
He can't help himself.
有射擊角度嗎?
You got the shot?
沒有
Negative.
該死 他在做什麼?
Damn it. What's he doing?
孩子出來了
Bringing the boy out.
咱把Hotch弄出來
Let's get hotch out of there.
他的決定
That's his call.
我們開著那卡車跑
Wewe drove around in that truck.
你讓自己兒子坐前排 好讓其他孩子感到安全?
You made your own son sit in front so the other boys would feel safe?
你...你把他們關籠子 我燒了他們的衣服
Youyou kept them in cages. I burnt their clothes.
等你完活了 就把他們埋了還讓他幫忙
And when you finished, you'd bury them and you made him help.
站起來 有點男人的樣子
get up. Pretend you're a man.
你喜歡小男孩 對吧?
You like little boys, don't you?
但也不能太小 因為那就不對了
But they can't be too small, 'cause that would be wrong.
他們有什麼特別? 讓你感到強大 感到像個男人?
What was it about them? They make you feel strong, make you feel like a man?
你閉嘴
You shut up.
是同意的意思嗎?
Is that a yes?
Darrin 這堻Q包圍了
Darrin. We're surrounded here.
警察隨時會突進這
The police are gonna storm in here any minute.
沒有武器的話 他們不會對你開槍
They will not shoot you if you are unarmed.
現在就把槍放下
You need to put the gun down now.
別...你別指使我!
Don'tdon'ttell me what to do!
別...
Don'tuhh
行動!
go,go!
怎麼了?
What happened?
我沒能阻止他
I couldn't stop him.
結束了 暫時結束
It's over. For now.
謝謝
Thank you.
我想你該跟那個人聊聊
There's someone i think you should talk to.
Tommy?
太對不起了
I'm so sorry.
為什麼?
What for?
我跑走了
For running away.
我們都跑了
We both ran.
是 但我把你丟下了
Yeah,but i left you behind.
他可能殺了你的
He could have killed you.
他沒有
He didn't.
因為我不再害怕他了
'Cause i wasn't afraid of him anymore.
你改變了一切 Tommy
You've changed everything,tommy.
我一直在等待你這麼個人
You're the one that i waited for.
是你救了我
You're the one that saved me.
"沒有可怕至極的證人 沒有恐怖之至的原告
"there is no witness so dreadful, "no accuser so terrible,
因為良心存在於每個人心中"
as the conscience that dwells in the heart of every man."
古希臘歷史學家 波堣顒
Polybius.
我知道你想說什麼
I know what you want to talk about.
兩個月前 我們不會打破Hotch的決定
2 months ago we wouldn't be breaking down hotch's decisions.
毫無疑問
There'd be no doubt.
兩個月前 他還有生活的盼頭 Rossi
2 months ago he had everything to live for,rossi.
現在他的家人都被帶走了
Now his family's just been taken away.
他要怎麼想其他的事?
How is he supposed to think about anything else?
他會讓Foyet贏多久?
How long is he gonna let foyet win?
我是說 咱抓到這傢伙的時候
I mean,come on, by the time we catch this guy,
Hotch內心的傷可能比外傷多得多
hotch could be more scarred on the inside than he is the outside.
Hotch冒了險 但我們救了那孩子
Hotch took a risk. But we saved that boy.
他冒了生命危險進去 我們絕不該這樣的 你知道
He put his life at risk in there, in ways that we are never supposed to,and you know it.
我可不打算待在一旁 看著他害死自己
I'm not about to stand by and watch this man kill himself.
你不會的
And you won't.
Rossi...
Hotch死了 Foyet就沒人可折磨了 那Hotch就贏了
If hotch is gone, foyet's got no one else to torture. Hotch wins.
但要是Hotch活著 卻無法看著兒子長大 那他就輸了
But if hotch lives but doesn't get to watch his son grow up, hotch loses.
你不用陪我上來的
You didn't have to walk me up here,you know.
我知道
I know.
你覺得Call會沒事嗎? 不知道
So you think call's gonna be ok? I don't know.
他找到答案了
He got his answers.
殺了那陰魂不散的人
He killed the man who haunted him.
還剩下什麼?
And what else is there?
遭折磨的日子
The years of torture.
覺得他能忘懷嗎? 怎麼會?
Think he'll get over that? How could he?
但至少不會再感覺孤獨無助了
But at least he doesn't have to feel like he's alone anymore.
他誰都沒有
He doesn't have anyone.
他有Tommy 他不是一個人
He has tommy. He's not alone.
睡會吧 你也是
Get some sleep. You,too.
犯罪心理 第五季 第2集 精神折磨
== 結束 ==
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode02 Haunted